# HUMBERTO GARCÍA

## - ios engineer -

## ABOUT ME

I am a solution-focused software developer with experience in native iOS applications, with constant pursue of excellence and knowledge in order to deliver high-quality products, highly collaborative and lover of learning. Passionate in creating communities that help us grow in our careers, always open to learning new technologies. Accustomed to working in agile environments, currently growing in Apple ecosystem.

## EDUCATION

## Information Technology (IT) Engineering

Universidad Politécnica de Tlaxcala, Sept 2019 - Dec 2022:

- Awarded with "Mejores Mil de Tlaxcala" and "Excelencia UPTx" scholarships.
- Participated with team in development of two systems for college utilizing PHP Framework.

## **Mechatronics Engineering**

Benemérita Universidad Autónoma de Puebla, Sept 2016 - Jun 2019

#### EXPERIENCE

## Web Developer Intern

Grupo ABX - Tlaxcala, México. April, 2022 - July, 2022:

- Prioritized and problem-solved several tasks concurrently with minimum supervision.
- Studied user requirements to gain strong understanding of Project initiatives and deadlines.
- Built products from scratch using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, CodeIgniter, Git, and MySQL.

## **Software Engineer Intern**

Deloitte - Queretaro, México, November, 2021 - January, 2022:

- Used interpersonal and communication skills to enrich team collaboration on Guidewire training project.
- Wrote Gosu (Java) scripts for practices, indexes, tables and gueries analyses.
- Built functional interfaces using Guidewire suit through Gosu code and SQL queries.
- Interacted efficiently with different trainers, being Indians the ones I interacted the most.

## **Front End Intern**

Centro de tecnologías creativas La Colmena - Tlaxcala, México, September, 2021 - January, 2022:

- Collaborated with multi-disciplinary teams to create web platform to show Tlaxcala's fauna specimens.
- Created interfaces using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Reveal.js.
- Implemented Scrum methodology for agile deliveries to the project and taught Git to Devt. team members.

#### SKILLS

Soft: Collaborative, Communicative, Analytical, Team Player, Supportive, Resilient, Empathic, Leadership, Flexible, Objective oriented, Adaptable, Motivational, Self-Taught, Inclusive, Team work, Always energic to learn new things.

Technical: Swift, UlKit, Autolayout, Cocoa Touch, Object Oriented Programming, Protocol Oriented Programming, Swift UI, CocoaPods, Core Data, UserDefaults, URLSession, Alamofire, RESTful APIs, MVC, MVVM, VIPER (Basic), SQL, NoSQL, Firebase, Unit Testing (currently learning), Scrum, Git, Github, Postman.

Languages: Advanced Technical Conversational English (C1), Native Spanish Speaker, Basic German (A2)

## **PROJECTS**

- Who is that Pokemon? UIKit: https://github.com/bertochgg/wholsThatPokemon-iOS.git
- Twitter Clone UIKit: https://github.com/bertochgg/twitter-clone-iOS.git
- Game Videos SwiftUI: https://github.com/bertochgg/GameVideos-iOS.git



Tlaxcala, México











